<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>thomas strömberg</title><link>https://libthom.so/</link><description>Recent content on thomas strömberg</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 11:36:17 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://libthom.so/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>OpenBSD on the Framework laptop</title><link>https://libthom.so/posts/2022/openbsd-framework-laptop/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 11:36:17 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://libthom.so/posts/2022/openbsd-framework-laptop/</guid><description>While preparing for my first week at Chainguard, the CEO mentioned that I should order my own laptop. As a ~15 person startup, there isn&amp;rsquo;t an IT department to handle these sorts of things.
In 2022, the default laptop of choice for a software engineer working on cloud infrastructure is the Apple M1 Powerbook. They hit nearly all the checkboxes: a great screen, powerful CPUs, and battery life that is the envy of any laptop in their class.</description></item><item><title>Hand-carving a bicycle</title><link>https://libthom.so/posts/2022/handcarved-bicycle/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://libthom.so/posts/2022/handcarved-bicycle/</guid><description>After dumping 60 hours into hand-carving a custom bicycle frame, I can say with high probability that you probably shouldn&amp;rsquo;t do so. Before I convince you of this, let me describe how I went about it.
A brief history of my bike builds Five years ago, while recovering from a broken foot, I ordered the Calfee DIY Bamboo Bicycle Kit to give me something to do. The kit provides the bamboo, the tools, the diagrams, and instructional videos.</description></item><item><title>My first 15k</title><link>https://libthom.so/posts/2022/first-15k/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://libthom.so/posts/2022/first-15k/</guid><description>Yesterday, I ran further than I have ever run before: 15k (9.6mi). Today, my legs feel sore and stiff, as if I am walking around on knees made up of chipped pallasite.
I trained for two months, but as you can see from the above chart, I only ran past the 7-mile range once.
I can make all sorts of excuses as to why I didn&amp;rsquo;t train more, but a significant reason for it was pain.</description></item><item><title>The anatomy of a great playbook entry</title><link>https://libthom.so/posts/2021/playbook-anatomy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://libthom.so/posts/2021/playbook-anatomy/</guid><description>What if you could easily reduce the length of outages by 3X?
According to the SRE book, &amp;ldquo;recording the best practices ahead of time in a playbook produces roughly a 3x improvement in MTTR&amp;rdquo;. This improvement mirrors my experience with well-written playbooks.
So what makes a playbook entry &amp;ldquo;great&amp;rdquo;?
Philosophy Remember how you felt in your first on-call rotation, when you were paged at 3am for a system you barely understood?</description></item><item><title>Motivating Software Engineering Teams</title><link>https://libthom.so/posts/2021/swe-motivation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://libthom.so/posts/2021/swe-motivation/</guid><description>Empathy, purpose, craftsmanship.
Empathy The key to motivating a team is to identify what motivates the people that make up the team, with enough empathy to put yourself in their shoes.
Everyone wants to be happy, but everyone has their unique path to happiness. Learning the career and life goals of everyone on the team allows you to prime the right tasks for them at the right time.
Asking people directly, &amp;ldquo;What motivates you as a software engineer?</description></item><item><title>Tesla Model Y: below-zero family camping</title><link>https://libthom.so/posts/2021/y-below-zero/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://libthom.so/posts/2021/y-below-zero/</guid><description>TL;DR: If you think outside of the box, you can sleep 4 with full climate control for a cost of 10-12% battery usage per night, even in freezing temperatures.
When we bought our Tesla Model Y in December, the intent was to roughly recreate the experiences of our trusty 1971 VW Bus, but in electric form.
With all the cargo space, and the availability of great mattress options, such as the Tesmat, one can get pretty close to a passenger-van conversion.</description></item><item><title>Go &amp; secondary groups: a kaniko adventure!</title><link>https://libthom.so/posts/2021/kaniko-groups/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://libthom.so/posts/2021/kaniko-groups/</guid><description>Originally posted on my personal blog in April 2020I wanted to get my feet wet with understanding Kaniko, an open-source in-cluster builder for Docker images. I happen to work with one of the maintainers, Tejal, and I asked her if there was any interesting UNIX-internals sort of bugs that might be interesting.
Here&amp;rsquo;s the mystery issue: &amp;ldquo;The USER command does not set the correct gids, so extra groups are dropped&amp;rdquo;. Here&amp;rsquo;s an example to reproduce it:</description></item><item><title>Persistent multi-user Docker on macOS</title><link>https://libthom.so/posts/2021/shared-docker-mac/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://libthom.so/posts/2021/shared-docker-mac/</guid><description>Need to make Docker on macOS available to any user who connects in remotely? It can be done!
First, be aware that docker is not designed to be securely shared among multiple users. Please assume that anyone who has access to docker is effectively equivalent to `root'.
This assumes that users will be interacting with docker via the command-line, rather than graphically. It also assumes that the environment is such that allows a single user to be automatically logged into via the GUI, but this is mostly out of laziness rather than an underlying technical restriction.</description></item><item><title>About Thomas</title><link>https://libthom.so/about/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 1978 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://libthom.so/about/</guid><description>Born in Sweden, raised in the United States, and settled in San Francisco.
I&amp;rsquo;ve spent most of my career attempting to replace myself with a tiny shell script. This includes a 15-year stint at Google, where I worked in a variety of positions across Hardware Operations, Site Reliability Engineering, Security, and Cloud.
My primary interests are open-source software, cycling, and photography.</description></item><item><title>Blogroll</title><link>https://libthom.so/blogroll/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://libthom.so/blogroll/</guid><description>As one of the last RSS hold-outs, I use Feedly to keep track of new ideas shared online. Here&amp;rsquo;s who I follow:
Inspiring Managers Cindy Sridharan Reliability Engineering Charity Majors Surfing Complexity by Lorin Hochstein Security Geeks Ariadne&amp;rsquo;s Space by Ariadne Conill KrebsOnSecurity by Brian Krebs Open-Source Adventures in BSD flak by Ted Unangst hubertf by Hubert Feyrer jmmv by Julio Merino joshua stein Lorin Hochstein Marianne Bellotti Michael Stapelberg p(retired) by Stefan Hajnoczi Steve Morgan Solène Rapenne That Grumpy BSD Guy by Peter N.</description></item></channel></rss>