<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>tech on thomas strömberg</title><link>https://libthom.so/tags/tech/</link><description>Recent content in tech on thomas strömberg</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 11:36:17 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://libthom.so/tags/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>OpenBSD on the Framework laptop</title><link>https://libthom.so/posts/2022/openbsd-framework-laptop/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 11:36:17 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://libthom.so/posts/2022/openbsd-framework-laptop/</guid><description>While preparing for my first week at Chainguard, the CEO mentioned that I should order my own laptop. As a ~15 person startup, there isn&amp;rsquo;t an IT department to handle these sorts of things.
In 2022, the default laptop of choice for a software engineer working on cloud infrastructure is the Apple M1 Powerbook. They hit nearly all the checkboxes: a great screen, powerful CPUs, and battery life that is the envy of any laptop in their class.</description></item><item><title>The anatomy of a great playbook entry</title><link>https://libthom.so/posts/2021/playbook-anatomy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://libthom.so/posts/2021/playbook-anatomy/</guid><description>What if you could easily reduce the length of outages by 3X?
According to the SRE book, &amp;ldquo;recording the best practices ahead of time in a playbook produces roughly a 3x improvement in MTTR&amp;rdquo;. This improvement mirrors my experience with well-written playbooks.
So what makes a playbook entry &amp;ldquo;great&amp;rdquo;?
Philosophy Remember how you felt in your first on-call rotation, when you were paged at 3am for a system you barely understood?</description></item><item><title>Motivating Software Engineering Teams</title><link>https://libthom.so/posts/2021/swe-motivation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://libthom.so/posts/2021/swe-motivation/</guid><description>Empathy, purpose, craftsmanship.
Empathy The key to motivating a team is to identify what motivates the people that make up the team, with enough empathy to put yourself in their shoes.
Everyone wants to be happy, but everyone has their unique path to happiness. Learning the career and life goals of everyone on the team allows you to prime the right tasks for them at the right time.
Asking people directly, &amp;ldquo;What motivates you as a software engineer?</description></item><item><title>Go &amp; secondary groups: a kaniko adventure!</title><link>https://libthom.so/posts/2021/kaniko-groups/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://libthom.so/posts/2021/kaniko-groups/</guid><description>Originally posted on my personal blog in April 2020I wanted to get my feet wet with understanding Kaniko, an open-source in-cluster builder for Docker images. I happen to work with one of the maintainers, Tejal, and I asked her if there was any interesting UNIX-internals sort of bugs that might be interesting.
Here&amp;rsquo;s the mystery issue: &amp;ldquo;The USER command does not set the correct gids, so extra groups are dropped&amp;rdquo;. Here&amp;rsquo;s an example to reproduce it:</description></item><item><title>Persistent multi-user Docker on macOS</title><link>https://libthom.so/posts/2021/shared-docker-mac/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://libthom.so/posts/2021/shared-docker-mac/</guid><description>Need to make Docker on macOS available to any user who connects in remotely? It can be done!
First, be aware that docker is not designed to be securely shared among multiple users. Please assume that anyone who has access to docker is effectively equivalent to `root'.
This assumes that users will be interacting with docker via the command-line, rather than graphically. It also assumes that the environment is such that allows a single user to be automatically logged into via the GUI, but this is mostly out of laziness rather than an underlying technical restriction.</description></item></channel></rss>